William Neil Smith papers, 1829-1975 (Bulk 1944-1970)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
William N. Smith papers, 1829-1975 (Bulk 1944-1970)
MS 316
Smith, William Neil, 1920-
This collection is divided into seven series: Biographical Information, General Correspondence, Writings and Publisher Correspondence, Field Notebooks and Logs, Research Files, Audio-Visual Media, and Supplemental Material. The collection includes biographical information, correspondence, writings, publications, field notebooks, field research data sheets, subject files, bibliography cards, photographs, negatives, color slides, motion picture film, and sound recordings, chiefly from 1944-1970, of William Neil Smith, relating to his anthropological field work amongst the Seri Indians of Tiburon Island and the northwest coast of Sonora, Mexico.
24 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
William Neil "Bill" Smith, Jr. was born May 5, 1920, at New York City (Broad Street Hospital, Manhattan), New York, the son of William Neil Smith, an architect, and Florence E. Derby. After his father died in 1934, Bill and his mother moved to Arizona. He attended high school at the Southern Arizona School (Sabino Canyon) in Tucson, 1934-1936 and the Palo Verde Ranch School in Mesa, 1937-1938. He attended the University of Arizona from 1939-42 and 1946-48, studying under Byron Cummings(Kinishba Ruins-Fort Apache Reservation-University of Arizona Summer School, Department of Archaeology) and Edward Spicer. He worked in the summer of 1937 at the University of Arizona Archaeological Field School held at the Kinishba Ruins on the White Mountain Apache Reservation. He graduated in May 1948 with an A.B. in Anthropology. He took graduate course work in 1950. He also served briefly in the Army in 1944-45.
From 1945-1967, Smith made many extended ethnographical field trips to Sonora, Mexico, to study the Seri Indians at Desemboque and Tiburon Island. His research included lifestyle, customs, language, genealogy, kinship, and cultural changes due to the influence of outsiders. He assisted the Seris by bringing much needed medicines and supplies to them. On four occasions, he brought groups of Seris to the United States to experience different cultures. He sought to educate people in the United States and Mexico about Seri culture and the problem of cultural change affecting the Seris through numerous lectures, publications, and film projects.
After concluding his studies in Sonora, Smith during three trips to Asia (1971-1972, 1975-1982, 1985-1993) carried out anthropological research in Australia, Bali, Thailand, and the Maldive Islands where he completed a research paper for the Republic of Maldives Department of Education on Islamic Youth, Development from Birth to 20 Years in 1992. He also contributed four detailed manuscripts to the Australian Department of Aboriginal Affairs - Alice Springs, Northern Territory covering research and participant observer studies of tribal problems in the Northern Territories (1988-1991) and lectures. Since his return from third trip to Asia and Australia, Smith has lectured on Islamic culture and worked on various articles related to Southwestern and Sonoran archaelogical data from his earlier unpublished notes.
Organization
This collection is organized into seven series:
Series I: Biographical Information, 1946-1971
Series II: General Correspondence, 1942-1975
Series III: Writings, 1829-1974
Series IV: Field Notebooks and Logs, 1945-1966
Series V: Research Files, 1890-1975
Series VI: Audio-Visual Media, 1922-1974
Series VII: Supplemental Material, 1950-1960
Scope and Content Note
This collection is divided into seven series: Biographical Information, General Correspondence, Writings and Publisher Correspondence, Field Notebooks and Logs, Research Files, Audio-Visual Media, and Supplemental Material. The first series consists of William Neil Smith's resumes, educational records, personal calendar records and biographical clippings, plus lists of materials collected during his studies. The second series is Smith's correspondence with archaeologists, colleagues, officials, publishers and friends regarding his studies of the Seri Indians.
The third series is divided into two sub-series. The first sub-series contains published and unpublished articles about the Seri by William Neil Smith. The second sub-series contains published and unpublished articles by other authors which were collected by Smith.
The fourth series consists of William Neil Smith's personal notebooks and field logs. These contain notes on each visit to Seri Country including itineraries, purchases, mileage logs and names of contacts.
The fifth series, Research Files, is divided into four sub-series. The first sub-series, "Census and Genealogy," consists of Smith's detailed records of the Seri population, including names, dates of birth, marriage and death, and kinship. Smith's filing system of index cards using various color coding has been preserved. The second sub-series is the Sea Turtle Figurine Study, which includes drafts of a manuscript about the study, photographs and sketches of the figurines, Smith's classification system, and related correspondence. The third sub-series consists of documentation and notes regarding Smith's Seri film projects, including correspondence with Walt Disney Studios. The fourth sub-series consists of subject files dealing with various aspects of Seri culture and outside contacts with the Seri. There are also miscellaneous records of Smith's associations with various societies, schools and museums.
The sixth series is audio-visual materials and is divided into four sub-series: photographs and negatives, color slides, motion picture film, and sound recordings. All of these materials were produced by Smith during his visits with the Seri Indians. Additional photographs can be found in the series, Research Files.
The last series is supplemental material consisting of posters advertising his lectures, display cards and sketches.
Smith, William Neil, 1920- -- Archives; Cummings, Byron, 1860-1954; Di Peso, Charles C. (Charles Corradino), b. 1920; Hodge, Frederick Webb, 1864-1956; Moser, Edward; Moser, Mary Beck, 1924-; Sauer, Carl Otwin, 1889-1975; Spicer, Edward Holland, 1906-1983; Montano family; American Friends Service Committee; Ethnohistory -- Mexico -- Sonora (State); Face painting -- Mexico -- Sonora (State); Indian baskets -- Mexico -- Sonora (State); Puberty rites -- Mexico -- Sonora (State); Seri Indians; Seri Indians -- Census; Seri Indians -- Cultural assimilation; Seri Indians -- Genealogy; Seri Indians -- Kinship; Seri Indians -- Music; Seri Indians -- Religion; Seri language; Bow and arrow making -- Mexico -- Sonora (State); Fire-making; Indian wood-carving -- Mexico -- Sonora (State); Indians of Mexico -- Social life and customs; Seri Indians -- Boats; Seri Indians -- Bone carving; Seri Indians -- Games; Seri Indians -- Pottery; Seri Indians -- Rites and ceremonies; Yuman Indians; Infiernillo Straits (Mexico); Desemboque (Sonora, Mexico); Kino Bay (Mexico); San Esteban Island (Mexico); Sonora (Mexico: State) -- Description and travel; Tiburon Island (Mexico); Tecomate (Sonora, Mexico); Patos Island (Mexico); Correspondence; Photographs; Notebooks
Container List
- Series I: Biographical Information, 1946-1971
  - Clippings. 1947-1959 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Education: Schools. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Education: Schools. Anthropology seminar: Social Organization of Papago Indians / Ruth Underhill, (under direction of Edward Spicer). 1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - General -- Miscellaneous. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Poems, philosophy, doodles. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Resumes and Seri field study chronology. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Calendar records of visits to Seri country: Desemboque and Tiburon Island, (includes information on births). 1946-1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Desemboque robbery. November 1950 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Grant proposals. 1948-1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Peace Corps, (application only). 1962 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Southwest Museum - Description of Seri materials, (Smith was an official collector for the Southwest Museum, appointment by Frederic W. Hodge). 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Hancock Foundation - Description of Seri materials (proposed sale). 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Amerind Foundation - Description of Seri materials, (for Charles DiPeso). 1954 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Arizona State Museum - Description of Seri materials, (Bill Wasley, Bernard Fontana - exhibit on Seri Culture, under Bob Baker and Ernie Leavitt). 1960s, November 1970-Spring 1971 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Series II: General Correspondence, 1942-1975
  - Irvin Ashkenazy - Proposed article. 1950-1955 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Byron Cummings, (related to Apache studies). 1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Leonora S. Curtin. 1949-1951 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Jack Danciger. 1955 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Edward H. Davis. 1947-1949 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Charles C. Di Peso. 1956-1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Clark Field. 1947-1953 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - John S. Garth. 1951 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Howard S. Gentry. 1951 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Frances Gillmor. 1969 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Frederick W. Hodge, Southwest Museum. 1947-1955 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Otis S. Marston. 1949 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Edward and Mary Beck Moser. 1953-1965 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Stuart H. Perry. 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Carl Sauer. 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Carl Schuster. 1955-1964 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Edward Spicer. 1951-1965 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Charles and Patricia Vaurie, American Museum of Natural History. 1952 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - W. N. Smith to his mother, Florence Smith. 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous. 1945-1975 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous, regarding Seri and other topics. 1943-1967 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Publishers, regarding Seri articles by W. N. Smith. 1949-1961 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Mexican anthropologists. 1947-1954 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Mexican government agencies and officials. 1946-1960 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Letters of recommendation for W. N. Smith. 1947-1955 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Series III: Writings, 1829-1974
  - Writings by William Neil Smith -- published
    - The Papago Game of "Gince Goot," ( Masterkey). 1945 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - "Seri Photographs, 1948," ( Masterkey). 1951 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - "Island That Time Forgot," ( Colliers). 1951 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - "Why Bring Seri Indians From Tiburón Island to Visit the United States," ( Masterkey). 1951 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - "Origin of Seri Indian Legends, the Sea-horse Story," ( Masterkey). 1958 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - "Observations Regarding Seri Indian Basketry," ( Kiva). 1959 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - The Seri Indians, by Ted De Grazia and W. N. Smith (manuscript draft of preface & introduction). 1970 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - The Seri Indians: A Primitive People of Tiburón Island, by Ted De Grazia with William Neil Smith. 1970 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - "The Seri Indians and the Sea Turtles," ( Journal of Arizona History). 1974 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Writings by William Neil Smith -- unpublished
    - Report on Seris from Visit to Tiburón Island. September 10-11, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Outlines and notes. 1947 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - History of the Seri Indians. 1947 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Papago-Seri Chronology. ca. 1950 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Field Ethnology - Letter report to Carl Sauer, University of California - Berkeley. 1950 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Why Study Seri Indians. 1950-1951 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Report on Seri film plan. ca. 1951 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Seri Ethnohistory, 1890-1953 (1); also, conclusions, addenda and short version presented at American Anthropological Association (A.A.A.) meeting, Tucson. 1953 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Seri Ethnohistory, 1890-1953 (2). 1953 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Seri Ethnohistory, 1890-1953 (3) - short version presented at A.A.A. meeting, Tucson. 1953 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Seri Ethnohistory, 1890-1953 (4) - version sent to American Anthropologist. 1954 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Seri Ethnohistory, 1890-1953 (5) - version sent to Charles H. Lowe, Jr., Zoology Department, University of Arizona. 1954 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Research report sent to Manuel Gamio, Instituto Indigenista Interamericano. 1954 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Culture change - Letter report to Ned Spicer, University of Arizona. 1962 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Apache-Seri Contacts in the Seri Area, 19th Cen. 1965 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Culture change, 1950-1965; The Advent of Christianity Among the Seri, by W.N. Smith and Zip Dobyns, 1966 1966 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Research on Seri - Letter report to Howard Baldwin, Sensory Systems Laboratory, Tucson, (C-14 data). 1966 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - The Seri Indians, A Coastal and Desert Island People by W. N. Smith and Ernest Leavitt (in association with exhibit at Arizona State Museum, Nov. 1970-May 1971). 1970 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Writings by other authors -- published
    - Travels in the Interior of Mexico in 1825, 1826, 1827, 1828, by Lieut. R.W.H. Hardy [chapters on Seri]. 1829 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - The Most Primitive American Savages, by Waldon Fawcett. 1901 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - The Wildest of Our Tribes - Seriland and the Seri, by W.J. McGee. 1901 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Notes on the Indians of Sonora, Mexico, by Aleš Hrdli_ka. 1904 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Serian, Tequistlatecan, and Hokan, by A.L. Kroeber. 1915 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - A Mexican Land of Canaan, by Frederick Simpich. 1919 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Our Indian Neighbors in Mexico, by M.E. Edwards. 1919 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Indians of the Sea, by Alvin E. Moore. 1930 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Sons of the Stone Age - The Seri - Modern Mexico's Most Savage Indians, by Roberto Thompson. 1931 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Region de los Seris Situacion Geographica, by Baltasar Samped. 1933 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Juan Tomas, War Chief of the Seris, by Edward H. Davis. 1933 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Missione per lo Studio delle Popolazioni Indigene del Messico, by Giuseppe E. Genna. 1933-1934 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Una Expedicion a la Isla del Tiburon - Vida, Costumbres y Tradiciones de los Indios Seris, by Giovanni Masturzi. 1934 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Premiers résultats d'une expédition italo-mexicaine parmi les populations indigènes et métisses du Mexique, by Corrado Gini. 1934 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Savages in Uncle Sam's Back Yard, by Richard Hallibuton. 1934 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Race Suicide Threat of Seris Disclosed, by Ernest B. Ehrke. 1936 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - 200 Miles to the Stone Age, by Robert M. Hyatt. 1936 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Children of the Ancients in Pacific Mexico, by Phil Hanna. 1936 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - North America's Most Primitive Savages, by Sydney H. Parsons. 1937 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Face Painting is Art to Seri Indian Girl. 1939 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Seris O Kunkak, by Francisco Rojas Gonzalez. 1941 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Los Seris, by Luis Arturo Gonzalez Bonilla. 1941 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Seri Indians on Tiburon Island, by Julian D. Hayden. 1942 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Memorial de su jira placer y de observación por la Península de la Baja California, durante el mes de abril de 1943, by Jack Danciger. 1943 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Some Ethnobotanical Notes on the Seri Indians, by E. Yale Dawson. 1944 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - I Seri Contributo alla conoscenza delle razze indigene del Messico, by Giuseppe Genna. 1944 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - The Savage Seris of Sonora, by Edward Davis and E. Yale Dawson. 1945 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Mis Amigos Los Seris, by Roberto Thomson. 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - The Stone-Age Men of 1947, by Cameron Shipp. 1947 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Seri's Last Stand, by Grancel Fitz, (color photographs/W.N.Smith). 1948 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Throwback to Stone Age Man is Found on Island near Los Angeles, by Gray Willson. 1949 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Primitivos del Norte, by I.N.A.H., Museo Nacional de Antropologia. ca. 1950 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - America Indigena. 1950 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - The Seris: Tribe of the North of Mexico, by Otilia Meza Soto. 1951 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - La Resurreción de los Seris, by Cesar Lizardi Ramos. 1952 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Articles and brief notes in Boltin Indigenista. 1952-1961 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Una Tribu Perdida en la Isla de Tiburón, de Felipe Bustamante, 1953 1953 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Los Seris, Antes y Hoy, by Carmen Cook de Leonard. 1953 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Trouble Over Tiburon, by Franz Kurth. 1953 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - America's Most Depraved Tribe, by George Spencer. 1954 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Mexico Struggles to Save a People, by Victor Alba. 1954 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - They Wouldn't Be Civilized, by Clifford L. Burdick. 1954 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Occurence (sic) of Zalophus californianus in the Gulf of California, by Robert B. Chiasson. 1954 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - I Faced Death in the Lost World, by Gerald Kendrick. 1955 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Some Clay Figurines and Seri Dolls from Coastal Sonora, Mexico, by Roger C. Owen; A Seri Fertility Figurine from Bahia Kino, Sonora, by George E. Fay; Artifacts from Estero Tastiota, Sonora, Mexico, by Frank M. Holzkamper; Notes on the Archaeology of the Central Coast of Sonora, Mexico, by Julian D. Hayden. 1956 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Articles from Acción Indigenista. 1957-1959 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Demografia de los Seris, by Ricardo Pozas. 1958 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Expedition for Seri Gold is Epic Story of Hardship, by Roscoe G. Willson. 1958 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - The Seris - Indians That Time Forgot, by Robert M. Hyatt. 1958 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - The Seri Indians - The People That Time Passed By. 1958 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Nature and Origin of the "Seri Boot", by Ronald L. Ives. 1959 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - La Tribu Seri, by Horacio Sobarzo. 1960 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Seri Indian Figurines, by James Manson. 1961 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Treasure of Tiburon, by Myron Brenton. 1962 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - The Dictionary of Anthropology, by Wolfgang H. Lindig. 1962 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Über die Bestattung bei den Seri in Sonora, Mexiko, by Wolfgang Lindig. ca. 1963 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - The Collective Suicide of the Seri Nation. 1963 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Seri Bands, by Edward Moser. 1963 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - I Can Never Go Back to Tiburon, by Al P. Yorick. 1963 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Tree Burial Among the Seri Indians, by Wolfgang H. Lindig. 1964 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Seri Blue, by Mary Beck Moser; Seri Blue - An Explanation, by H. Wesley Peirce. 1964 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - The Seri Indians in 1692 as Described by Adamo Gilg, S.J., translated & edited by Charles Di Peso and Daniel S. Matson. 1965 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - The Seri Indians, Museum Exhibit, Bowers Memorial Museum. 1965 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Seri Country Today, by Ted Trevor. 1965 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Segunda Cartilla Seri and Cuarta Cartilla Seri, by Instituto Linguistico de Verano. 1966 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Recent Seri Culture Change, by John A. Woodward. 1966 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Seri Pottery, by Thomas Bowen and Edward Moser; Seri Clay Figurines, by E. Moser and Richard S. White; Seri Ironwood Carving, by Bernice Johnston. 1968 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - "Seri Studies," (7 articles in The Kiva). 1970 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Writings by other authors -- unpublished
    - Informe del Intendente de Sonora acerca de la ilegitimidad del Monasterio de Monserrat, para reclamar derecho de propiedad sobre las tierras repartidas a los Seris en el Pueblo de Seris. 1772 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Diario de operaciones y novedades ocurridas en la marcha sobre la isla del Tiburon, by Francisco Andrade. 1844 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Portion of a Typed Diary, written by George F. Flavell. 1894 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - The Tribe of Seri Indians, by C.M. Ginther. 1907 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Makes Study of the Seris on Tiburon Island - Michael Williams Declares Indians are not Canibals (sic). ca. 1930 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Isla del Tiburon. 1943 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Report to American Friends Service Committee on Seri Indians, by Norman Krekler. 1949 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Los Indios Seris, by M. Bernal Huetomu. 1950 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - The Significance of Baja California for Anthropological Research, by Ralph Beals. 1952 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - La Resurreción de los Seris, by Cesar Ramos. 1952 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - The Papagos and Seris, by Bonaventure Oblasser. 1957 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Mexican Trip - 1957, by Frederic C. Alexander. 1957 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Informe de la prima brigada de exploracion sanitaria a la Tribu Seri en el ano de 1959, by Ramiro Quezada et al. 1959 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Bandas Seri, by Eduardo Moser. ca. 1960 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Los Seris, by Ricardo Pozas, I.N.A.H. 1961 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Demographic Analysis of Four Small Ethnic Groups in the West, by Henry Pang. 1967 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Miscellaneous articles and notes on the Seri. 1935-1961 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Miscellaneous articles on Sonoran archaeology. 1908-1967 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Western State Bulletin of the American Anthropological Association. 1949-1952 (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Series IV: Field Notebooks and Logs, 1945-1966
  - Seri Field Notes. 1946 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Seri Field Notes. 1947 (Box 6, Folder 2-4)
  - Seri Field Notes. 1948 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Seri Field Notes. 1949 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Seri Field Notes. 1950 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Seri Field Notes. 1951 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Seri Field Notes. 1952 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Seri Field Notes of Alfred F. Whiting. 1951 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Seri Field Logs. 1945-1946 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Seri Field Logs. 1946-1947 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Seri Field Logs. 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Seri Field Logs. 1950-1952 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Seri Field Logs. 1952-1953 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Seri Field Logs. 1954-1956 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Seri Field Logs. 1956-1959 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Seri Field Logs. 1959-1966 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Series V: Research Files, 1890-1975
  - Census and Genealogy
    - Census data -- Explanation of color code used for recording Seri genealogies. 1947-1953 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Census data -- Index to genealogies. ca. 1950 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Census data -- Notes regarding forms to be used for recording observations of Seri individuals (living). 1951 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Census data. 1960-1965 [includes some 1966-1970] (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Census data -- Copies of data cards. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Census data -- Miscellaneous notes Deaths before December 31, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Census data. December 31, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 7-8)
    - Census data, annotated. December 31, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Census data -- Notes. December 31, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Census data -- Genealogical charts. ca. 1947 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Census data -- Graphs and tables. 1948-1967 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Census data -- Individual record sheets. 1950 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Census data -- Miscellaneous notes. 1947-1955 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Census data -- Miscellaneous notes. 1950-1951 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Census data -- Miscellaneous notes. 1950-1952 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Census data -- Miscellaneous notes. 1958-1964 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Census data (Material for proposed monograph on 5-year population study of Seri 1948-1952). 1948-1954 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Census data -- Notebooks. 1948-1960 (Box 10, Folder 5)